<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: extension | Heartcode Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://heartcode.github.com/blog/categories/extension/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://heartcode.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-15T23:58:09+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://heartcode.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Robert Pataki]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[heartcode@robertpataki.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fixing the trailing slash issue in the invalid Chrome extension manifest file]]></title>
    <link href="http://heartcode.github.com/blog/2012/11/15/fixing-the-trailing-slash-issue-in-the-invalid-chrome-extension-manifest-file/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-15T23:45:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://heartcode.github.com/blog/2012/11/15/fixing-the-trailing-slash-issue-in-the-invalid-chrome-extension-manifest-file</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://heartcode.github.com/blog/2012/11/15/fixing-the-trailing-slash-issue-in-the-invalid-chrome-extension-manifest-file/"><img src="/images/posts/fixing-the-trailing-slash-issue-in-the-invalid-chrome-extension-manifest-file/fixing-the-trailing-slash-issue-in-the-invalid-chrome-extension-manifest-file.png" width="789" height="443" title="Trailing slash" alt="Trailing slash"></a></p>

<p>The other day I had some spare time and I thought it was a great opportunity to do some JavaScript code refactoring on my <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/fontier/dkbamaalakfhckcidgiigdinhcncaeae">Fontier Chrome extension</a>. The refactoring process didn’t take a long time, because the application itself is very simple. I tested the new version of the add-on in the newest <strong>Chrome (Version 23.0.1271.64)</strong> and in <strong>Canary (Version 25.0.1325.0 canary)</strong> and after seeing that it worked fine in both, I decided to update the extension in the Chrome Web Store.</p>

<p>After I finished refactoring my extension code I logged in to my Developer Dashboard and I updated the extension using the ZIP upload tool. When I was done with the update I removed the 0.3 version of Fontier from my Chrome and I went to the Chrome Store to install the new version. For some reason Chrome didn't let me install the extension :)</p>

<p>When I hit the 'Add to Chrome' button, the following error message popped up under the address bar:</p>

<blockquote><p>"Package is invalid. Details: 'Illegal path (absolute or relative with '..'): '/img/icon_48.png".</p></blockquote>

<h2>But that worked before...</h2>

<p>Fair enough, I thought I broke the <strong>manifest.json</strong> file. I was sure that apart from increasing the 'version' from '0.3' to '0.4' I didn't change anything, but I quickly scanned through the manifest to make sure everything was alright. Esentially everything was the same as it was before:</p>

<pre><code>{
  "name": "Fontier",
  "version" : "0.4",
  "minimum_chrome_version": "22.0.1229.79",
  "manifest_version": 2,
  "description" : "The quickest way to change the default font size in Chrome. Great for testing Responsive websites using em and percentage units.",
  "permissions": ["fontSettings"],
  "icons": {
    "16": "/img/icon_16.png",
    "48": "/img/icon_48.png",
    "128": "/img/icon_128.png"
  },
  "browser_action": {
    "default_icon": "/img/icon_48.png",
    "default_popup": "/html/popup.html"
  },
  "content_security_policy": "script-src 'self' https://ssl.google-analytics.com; object-src 'self'"
}
</code></pre>

<p>Obviously I triple checked the path of the icon files, but I couldn't see anything wrong with them, so I Googled the error message, and I'd found this <a href="https://groups.google.com/a/chromium.org/forum/?fromgroups=#!topic/chromium-extensions/4BSWseDPjZM">Google Groups thread</a>. So it seemed that I wasn't the only one with this problem. It looked like that something had changed in Chrome and it no longer liked the paths of the icons. The strange thing was that I couldn't find anything about any relevant changes in the API <a href="http://developer.chrome.com/extensions/manifest.html#icons">documentation</a> either.</p>

<p>I guess your first bet is to remove the trailing slash from the paths, and you're absoutely right! That was my first thing to do, but for some reason, when I updated the extension, it still didn't work. From that point I spent long hours of changing-zipping-uploading the extension but it kept throwing the error messages telling me that the manifest file was somewhat broken. After about 4 hours of trying I gave up… I thought it was probably Chrome being funny and I really had to wait until a new version comes out.</p>

<h2>The 'painful' aha moment</h2>

<p>I just couldn't let it go that easy :) The next day I spent another couple of hours of investigating the issue and I found that whenever one updates an extension, the old version gets cached for quite some time. It was a pretty painful lighbulb moment…</p>

<p>So I went back to my very initial idea of removing that cheeky trailing slash from every single file path in the manifest file and when I updated the extension I took my time and let the server to take its time as well… After about 5 minutes I saw that the very recent version showed up in the <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/fontier/dkbamaalakfhckcidgiigdinhcncaeae/details">Details panel</a> and when I hit the 'Add to Chrome' button, it worked!</p>

<p>I genuinely felt stupid for not taking the server caching into consideration, but at the same time I was super happy that eventually Fontier was back to action :)</p>

<p>So, just for your record, here is the new <strong>manifest.json</strong> file whithout any trailing slashes:</p>

<pre><code>{
  "name": "Fontier",
  "version" : "0.4",
  "minimum_chrome_version": "22.0.1229.79",
  "manifest_version": 2,
  "description" : "The quickest way to change the default font size in Chrome. Great for testing Responsive websites using em and percentage units.",
  "permissions": ["fontSettings"],
  "icons": {
    "16": "img/icon_16.png",
    "48": "img/icon_48.png",
    "128": "img/icon_128.png"
  },
  "browser_action": {
    "default_icon": "img/icon_48.png",
    "default_popup": "html/popup.html"
  },
  "content_security_policy": "script-src 'self' https://ssl.google-analytics.com; object-src 'self'"
}
</code></pre>

<h2>Lesson learnt</h2>

<p>So it turned out that it indeed was the trailing slash. I figure that something has changed in the extension packager and it no longer lets developers to use the trailing slash in file name paths - which is completely fine. The only problem whith that is that it is not documented and it turns out accidentally :) Luckily the problem wasn't a biggy, so it was pretty easy to sort.</p>

<p>I actually made the problem worse by not counting with the server caching and not checking the version numbers properly.</p>

<p>That tought me a damn good lesson of patience and to listen a bit more carefully to the tools that I use.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
